Guide to the Edwin Montefiore Borchard Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Selected Correspondence, 1913-1948; Series I; 5'6" (13 boxes)
  - Newton, Charles S., 1924 (Box 11, Folder 131)
  - Newton, Cleveland (*), 1926 (Box 11, Folder 132)
  - Newton, Walter H., 1923-1926 (Box 11, Folder 132)
  - Nicholson, Harold, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 132)
  - Norris, George W. (*), 1924-1941 (Box 11, Folder 133)
  - Nye, Gerald P. (*), 1934-1941 (Box 11, Folder 133)
  - Olds, Robert E., 1927 (Box 11, Folder 134)
  - Owen, Robert L. (*), 1923-1938 (Box 11, Folder 134)
  - Pan American Union
    See: box 11, folder 142
  - Parker, Edwin B., 1927 (Box 11, Folder 135)
  - Parsons, Charles., 1941-1945 (Box 11, Folder 135)
  - Patterson, Robert P., 1944-1945 (Box 11, Folder 135)
  - Peace Patriots., 1936 (Box 11, Folder 135)
  - Pepper, George Wharton. (*), 1938-1946 (Box 11, Folder 136)
  - Perkins, Frances., 1938 (Box 11, Folder 137)
  - Pershing, John J., 1942 (Box 11, Folder 137)
  - Pettengill, Samuel B., 1943 (Box 11, Folder 137)
  - Philbin, Philip J., 1945 (Box 11, Folder 138)
  - Phelps, Admiral W. W., 1935 (Box 11, Folder 138)
  - Pittman, Key, 1933, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 138)
  - Polk, Frank.L., 1919 (Box 11, Folder 138)
  - Post War World Council., 1942-1946 (Box 11, Folder 139, File 1)
    See also: box 12, folder 156 box 13, folders 166-168
  - Pound, Roscoe (*), 1912-1936 (Box 11, Folder 139, File 2)
  - Price, William Jennings, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 140)
  - The Progressive, 1943-1944 (Box 11, Folder 140)
  - Rankin, Jeannette, 1919 (Box 11, Folder 141)
  - Reed, David A., 1926-1932 (Box 11, Folder 141)
  - Reed, James, 1924 (Box 11, Folder 141)
  - Republican National Committee, 1932, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 141)
  - Research in International Law, 1942
    See: box 4, folders 56-61
  - Riesman, David Jr., 1942 (Box 11, Folder 142)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1941 (Box 11, Folder 142)
  - Rogers, James Grafton, 1932-1933 (Box 11, Folder 142)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1932-1934 (Box 11, Folder 142)
  - Root, Elihu, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 142)
  - Rowe, L. S., 1937 (Box 11, Folder 142)
  - Rubin, Morris
    See: box 11, folder 140
  - Rutledge, Wiley., 1943 (Box 11, Folder 143)
  - Sargeant, John G., 1926 (Box 11, Folder 144)
  - Sedwick, Ellery., 1935-1937 (Box 11, Folder 144)
  - Seymour, Charles., 1925, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 144)
  - Shanley, James A. (*), 1935-1939 (Box 11, Folder 145-146)
  - Shanley, James A. (*), 1940-1946 (Box 12, Folder 147-150)
  - Simonds, Frank H., 1932-1936 (Box 12, Folder 151)
  - Simons, F. M., 1925 (Box 12, Folder 151)
  - Shipstead, Hendrick., 1946 (Box 12, Folder 151)
  - Smith, Alfred., 1920 (Box 12, Folder 151)
  - Smoot, Reed, 1923 (Box 12, Folder 151)
  - Soule, George, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 151)
  - Starr, Hubert., 1937 (Box 12, Folder 152)
  - Stecher, Karl. (*), 1932-1945 (Box 12, Folder 152)
  - Stimson, Henry L., 1932, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 152)
  - Stone, Harlan. (*), 1924-1945 (Box 12, Folder 153)
  - Sulzberger, Arthur., 1923-1936 (Box 12, Folder 154)
  - Swanson, Claude., 1932 (Box 12, Folder 154)
  - Swing, Raymond G., 1935 (Box 12, Folder 154)
  - Taft, Robert A. (*), 1941-1946 (Box 12, Folder 155)
  - Taft, William Howard (*), 1923-1927 (Box 12, Folder 155)
  - Thomas, Elbert D., 1936-1939 (Box 12, Folder 156)
  - Thomas, Norman. (*), 1938-1946 (Box 12, Folder 156)
  - Tilson, John Q. (*), 1920-1927 (Box 12, Folder 156)
  - Tinkham, George Holden (*), 1926-1939 (Box 12, Folder 157-161)
  - Tinkham, George Holden (*), 1940-1946 (Box 12, Folder 162)
  - Today
    See: box 6, folder 86
  - Underhill, Charles L., 1922, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 163)
  - United States Senate Steering Committee, 1945-1946 (Box 12, Folder 163)
  - Vandenberg, Arthur H. (*), 1934-1946 (Box 12, Folder 164)
  - Viereck, George Sylvester (*), 1936-1943 (Box 13, Folder 165)
  - Villard, Oswald Garrison (*), 1919-1938, 1940-1946 (Box 13, Folder 166-168)
  - Wagner, Robert F., 1928-1938 (Box 13, Folder 169)
  - Walcott, Frederic C., 1932 (Box 13, Folder 169)
  - Walsh, Thomas J., 1926-1933 (Box 13, Folder 169)
  - Washington Herald, editor, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - Watson, James E., 1923, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - Wheeler, Burton K., 1943-1946 (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - Wiggins, Henry H., 1949 (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - Wigmore, John H. (*), 1911-1936 (Box 13, Folder 171)
  - Willis, Raymond E., 1945 (Box 13, Folder 171)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (*), 1927-1942 (Box 13, Folder 172)
  - Woolsey, Lester H., 1917-1919 (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - World Congress Against War., 1932 (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - World Unity Foundation, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - Wright, Quincy, 1918-1943 (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - Wynne, William H., 1942 (Box 13, Folder 173)
- General Correspondence, 1910-1947; Series II; 17' (41 boxes)
  The general correspondence is arranged chronologically by year, month, and day.
  - 1910-1913, 1916-1919 January (Box 14, Folder 174-187)
  - 1919 February - 1920 Jun, 1921-1923 November (Box 15, Folder 188-199)
  - 1923 December - 1924 October (Box 16, Folder 200-209)
  - 1924 November - 1925 March (Box 17, Folder 210-218)
  - 1925 April-November (Box 18, Folder 219-228)
  - 1925 November - 1926 April (Box 19, Folder 229-238)
  - 1926 April-November (Box 20, Folder 239-247)
  - 1926 December - 1927 July (Box 21, Folder 248-256)
  - 1927 August - 1928 March (Box 22, Folder 257-264)
  - 1928 April-December (Box 23, Folder 265-273)
  - 1929 January - November (Box 24, Folder 274-284)
  - 1929 December - 1930 June (Box 25, Folder 285-294)
  - 1930 July - December (Box 26, Folder 295-305)
  - 1931 January - July (Box 27, Folder 306-316)
  - 1931 August - 1932 March (Box 28, Folder 317-328)
  - 1932 March - October (Box 29, Folder 329-339)
  - 1932 October - 1933 March (Box 30, Folder 340-348)
  - 1933 March-October (Box 31, Folder 349-359)
  - 1933 October - 1934 March (Box 32, Folder 360-368)
  - 1934 March-October (Box 33, Folder 369-379)
  - 1934 November - 1935 May (Box 34, Folder 380-390)
  - 1935 May-December (Box 35, Folder 391-403)
  - 1936 January-May (Box 36, Folder 404-413)
  - 1936 June - 1937 February (Box 37, Folder 414-427)
  - 1937 February - 1937 August (Box 38, Folder 428-438)
  - 1937 September - 1938 February (Box 39, Folder 439-448)
  - 1938 February-June (Box 40, Folder 449-457)
  - 1938 July-December (Box 41, Folder 458-468)
  - 1939 January-April (Box 42, Folder 469-476)
  - 1939 May-November (Box 43, Folder 477-487)
  - 1939 December - 1940 April (Box 44, Folder 488-497)
  - 1940 May-November (Box 45, Folder 498-508)
  - 1940 December - 1941 July (Box 46, Folder 509-519)
  - 1941 August - 1942 April (Box 47, Folder 520-529)
  - 1942 May - 1943 April (Box 48, Folder 530-541)
  - 1943 April - 1944 January (Box 49, Folder 542-552)
  - 1944 January-October (Box 50, Folder 553-563)
  - 1944 November-1945 July (Box 51, Folder 564-576)
  - 1945 July - 1946 March (Box 52, Folder 577-587)
  - 1946 May-September (Box 53, Folder 588-596)
  - 1946 October - 1947 Jun, undated (Box 54, Folder 597-602)
- Subject Files: International Law & Foreign Affairs, 1913-1950; Series III; 19' 5" (47 boxes)
  Subject files are grouped in five sections according to subject. Materials within each folder are arranged chronologically.
  Section A: Disposition of enemy property: general legal issues
  Section B: Disposition of enemy property: specific cases
  Section C: War claims and arbitration
  Section D: Protection of private property of foreigners
  Section E: International law: conferences and miscellaneous research topics
  - Disposition of enemy property: general legal issues
    - Disposition of German property (Box 55, Folder 603)
    - Disposition of enemy property - research notes, memoranda, WW I (Box 55, Folder 604-608)
    - Disposition of enemy property - research notes, WW I (Box 55, Folder 609)
    - Disposition of enemy property - memoranda, 1929-1930 (Box 55, Folder 610)
    - Disposition of enemy property - memoranda, 1929-1930 (Box 56, Folder 611)
    - Disposition of enemy property - pamphlets, newspaper clippings, 1930 (Box 56, Folder 612)
  - Disposition of enemy property: specific cases
    - Alsace-Lorraine - sequestrated property, WW I (Box 56, Folder 613-615)
    - Australia - disposition of enemy property research report, WW I (Box 56, Folder 616)
    - Austria - disposition of enemy property, WW I (Box 56, Folder 617)
    - Belgium - sequestrated enemy property, WW I (Box 57, Folder 618)
    - Brazilian legislation on alien enemy property - research report, 1932 (Box 57, Folder 619)
    - British North Borneo - German property disposition, WW I (Box 57, Folder 620)
    - British Cameroons - ex-enemy immovable property disposal, 1926-1928 (Box 57, Folder 621)
    - British legislation affecting enemy property and interests - research report, WW I (Box 57, Folder 622)
    - Canada - sequestrated German property, 1930 (Box 57, Folder 623)
    - Ceylon - disposition of enemy property WW I (Box 57, Folder 624)
    - Chile - treatment of German vessels research memo, WW I (Box 57, Folder 625)
    - Cuba - disposition of enemy property research memo, WW I (Box 57, Folder 626)
    - France - German property, WW I (Box 57, Folder 627-629)
    - France - disposition of enemy property research memo, WW I (Box 58, Folder 630)
    - French legislation dealing with enemy property and interests - research report, WW I (Box 58, Folder 631)
    - German Southwest Africa - property disposition, WW I (Box 58, Folder 632)
    - Great Britain - German property, 1933 (Box 58, Folder 633-635)
    - Guatemala - disposition of enemy property research report, WW I (Box 58, Folder 636)
    - Haiti - disposition of German property research notes, WW I (Box 58, Folder 637)
    - Honduras - disposition of German property, WW I (Box 58, Folder 638)
    - Hungary - sequestrated property, 1935 (Box 58, Folder 639)
    - Italy - German property, 1920's (Box 58, Folder 640)
    - Italy - German property, 1920's (Box 59, Folder 641-642)
    - Japan - sequestrated German property, 1925-1927 (Box 59, Folder 643)
    - New Guinea - German property, WW I (Box 59, Folder 644-645)
    - New Zealand - German property, WW I (Box 59, Folder 646)
    - Peru - disposition of enemy property research report, WW I (Box 59, Folder 647)
    - South Africa - disposition of enemy property, WW I (Box 59, Folder 648)
    - South Africa - disposition of enemy property, research memoranda, WW I (Box 59, Folder 649)
    - Tanganyika - German property, WW I (Box 59, Folder 650)
    - Togo - German property, WW I (Box 59, Folder 651)
    - U.S. policy on sequestrated alien property Borah Bill for return of alien property, 1925 (Box 59, Folder 652-653)
    - U.S. policy on sequestrated alien property Borah Bill for return of alien property, 1925 (Box 60, Folder 654)
    - Uruguay - disposition of enemy property research report, WW I (Box 60, Folder 655)
    - Western Samoa - German property, WW I (Box 60, Folder 656)
    - Yugoslavia - disposition of enemy property, WW I (Box 60, Folder 657-658)
  - War claims and arbitration
    - War claims arbiter - memoranda, 1928-1929 (Box 60, Folder 659)
    - War claims arbiter - minutes, 1928-1929 (Box 60, Folder 660)
    - War claims correspondence, 1922-1928, 1931 (Box 60, Folder 661)
    - War claims - U.S. brief on compensation to German nationals for seized vessels, Circa 1928 (Box 60, Folder 662)
    - War claims - memoranda, clippings, 1920's - 1930's (Box 60, Folder 663)
    - War Claims Act settlement reports, 1935 (Box 60, Folder 664)
    - War claims - German sabotage awards, 1934-1940 (Box 61, Folder 665-668)
    - German claims, 1920's (Box 61, Folder 669-670)
    - German claims - research reports, 1933 (Box 61, Folder 671-672)
    - Mixed Claims Commission, U.S. and Germany Docket Nos. 8103, 8117, 1933 (Box 62, Folder 673)
    - Germany - reparations and foreign loans, 1925-1931 (Box 62, Folder 674)
    - Mixed Claims Commission, U.S. and Germany sabotage case decisions, 1932 (Box 62, Folder 675)
    - Reparations Commission - arbitral tribunal awards (Box 62, Folder 676-677)
    - Arbitral Tribunal, Award 3, 1928 (Box 62, Folder 678)
    - "Enemy Private Property in Previous Wars" by Joachim von Elbe (Box 62, Folder 679)
    - Alien property - bibliography, clippings, statutes, 1938-1939 (Box 62, Folder 680)
    - U.S., Austria and Hungary - Report of Dr. Phossinagg to Tripartite Claims Commission (Box 63, Folder 681)
    - Domestic Claims Commission - rules of procedure, 1931 (Box 63, Folder 682)
    - Alien property and war claims research, 1932-1936 (Box 63, Folder 683)
    - U. S. and Reparation Commission arbitration decision re: Standard Oil tankers, 1926 (Box 63, Folder 684)
    - War Claims Act - memoranda, research notes (Box 63, Folder 685)
    - War claims - S.S. La Campine Dossier, 1920 (Box 63, Folder 686)
    - War claims - S.S. La Flandre Dossier, 1925 (Box 63, Folder 687)
    - S.S. Dacia Case - research notes, documents (Box 63, Folder 688-690)
    - S.S. Dacia Case - research notes, documents (Box 64, Folder 691-695)
    - S.S. Seguranca Case - research notes (Box 64, Folder 696)
    - S.S. Seguranca Case - briefs (Box 65, Folder 697-698)
    - S.S. Seguranca Case - memoranda (Box 65, Folder 699-700)
    - S.S. Seguranca Case - U.S. answer to claimant's brief (Box 65, Folder 701)
    - S.S. Seguranca Case - reply of claimant to U.S. answer (Box 65, Folder 702)
    - S.S. Seguranca Case - U.S. brief (Box 65, Folder 703)
    - S.S. Seguranca Case, 1915-1934 (Box 65, Folder 704-705)
    - S.S. Seguranca Case, 1935-1939 (Box 66, Folder 706-707)
    - S.S. Seguranca Case - insurance policies, newsclippings (Box 66, Folder 708)
    - Reply brief of German shipowners to war claims arbiter - by E. M. Borchard, 1928 (Box 66, Folder 709)
    - Riedemann claims, 1920 - 1922 April (Box 66, Folder 710-712)
    - Riedemann claims, 1922 May - 1927 (Box 67, Folder 713-719)
    - Riedemann claims, 1927 - 1930 July (Box 68, Folder 720-725)
    - Riedemann claims, 1930 August - 1934 (Box 69, Folder 726-732)
    - Riedemann claims, 1935 - 1946 (Box 70, Folder 733-736)
    - Riedemann claims - memoranda, notes, undated (Box 70, Folder 737)
    - Riedemann claims - original documents (Box 70, Folder 738)
    - Riedemann claims - copies of documents used as evidence (Box 70, Folder 739)
    - Riedemann claims - copies of documents used as evidence (Box 70, Folder 740)
    - Lewis Gun Case, 1921-1922, 1933 February-1936, 1939-1941 (Box 71, Folder 741-748)
    - Lewis Gun Company v. Great Britain
      - documents (Box 71, Folder 749-752)
      - documents (Box 72, Folder 753)
  - Protection of private property of foreigners
    - Private property of foreigners in time of war, 1931-1940 (Box 72, Folder 754-759)
    - Private property of foreigners in time of war, 1943-1946 (Box 73, Folder 760-763)
    - Diplomatic protection of citizens abroad research notes, 1927-1931 (Box 73, Folder 764-767)
    - Diplomatic protection of citizens abroad research notes, miscellaneous (Box 73, Folder 768)
    - Diplomatic protection of citizens abroad newspaper clippings, 1930's (Box 73, Folder 769)
    - Diplomatic protection of citizens abroad research notes, miscellaneous (Box 74, Folder 770-773)
    - Mexican Law of Expropriation, 1933 (Box 74, Folder 774)
    - Claims against Mexico, 1920's - 1930's (Box 74, Folder 775)
    - Comision de Reclamaciones entre Mexico e Italia - Decisiones y Opiniones, 1927 (Box 75, Folder 776)
    - Decisions of German-Mexican Claims Commission Vol. I (Box 75, Folder 777)
    - Decisions of German-Mexican Claims Commission Vol. II (Box 75, Folder 778)
    - Syllabus of Decisions of German-Mexican Claims Commission (Box 76, Folder 779)
    - Claims Commission Rules, U.S. and Mexico research notes, 1933 (Box 76, Folder 780)
    - Mexican claims settlement, 1942 (Box 76, Folder 781-782)
    - French-Mexican Claims Commission, 1930 (Box 76, Folder 783)
    - "The Mexican Expropriations in International Law", 1938 (Box 76, Folder 784)
    - Mexican Supreme Court memoranda on sustaining confiscation of oil properties, 1940 (Box 76, Folder 785)
    - Mexican Petroleum Law of 1925 memorandum and text (Box 76, Folder 786)
    - Standard Oil "Uruguayan Situation", 1931-1935 (Box 77, Folder 787)
    - Standard Oil v. Mexico, 1938-1940 Feb, 1940 May, March (Box 77, Folder 788-792)
    - Standard Oil v. Mexico, 1940 April - 1941 May (Box 78, Folder 793-797)
    - Standard Oil Company, Mexico, 1941 June-August (Box 79, Folder 798)
    - Standard Oil v. Mexico, 1941 September-August (Box 79, Folder 799)
    - Standard Oil v. Mexico, 1941 October - 1942 March (Box 79, Folder 800-801)
    - Standard Oil v. Mexico, 1942 April-December (Box 80, Folder 802)
    - Standard Oil Company
      - Panay Incident claim, 1939-1942 (Box 80, Folder 803)
      - Bolivia, 1940-1942 (Box 80, Folder 804)
      - Belgium ship requisitions, 1941-1942 (Box 80, Folder 805)
      - Venezuela, 1941-1943 (Box 80, Folder 806)
      - miscellaneous, 1943-1946, 1924, 1940, 1941, 1936-1938 (Box 80, Folder 807-809)
      - miscellaneous, 1939-1941 (Box 81, Folder 810-811)
    - Anglo-Brazilian Joint Commission research notes, documents, 1859 (Box 81, Folder 812-813)
    - Argentina - claims against, 1850's (Box 81, Folder 814)
    - British and Venezuelan Claims Commission research notes, documents, 1868 (Box 81, Folder 815)
    - British claims, 1926-1928 (Box 81, Folder 816)
    - British claims - newspaper clippings, 1926-1928 (Box 81, Folder 817)
    - Didier Claim against Chile, 1942-1943 (Box 81, Folder 818)
    - Greek settlement of property claims research report, Circa 1933 (Box 81, Folder 819)
    - Haiti - claims settlement for Port-au-Prince disturbances of 1883-1884 (Box 82, Folder 820)
    - Haitian Claims Commission - opinions (French text) (Box 82, Folder 821)
    - Haitian Claims Commission decisions (French text) (Box 82, Folder 822)
    - Haitian Claims Commission (French text) (Box 82, Folder 823)
    - Haitian Claims Commission - claimants, 1919 (Box 82, Folder 824-826)
    - Haitian Claims Commission - briefs (Box 82, Folder 827)
    - Krueger Claim, 1927-1928 (Box 82, Folder 828)
    - Landrean Claim - U.S, v. Peru, 1921-1922 (Box 83, Folder 829)
    - Montevidean Claims - research notes, documents, 1863 (Box 83, Folder 830-831)
    - Pugh v. Panama, 1932 (Box 83, Folder 832)
    - South African claims - 19th century research notes (Box 83, Folder 833)
    - International claims cases
      - France (Box 83, Folder 834)
      - Germany (Box 83, Folder 835)
      - Greece (Box 83, Folder 836)
      - Italy (Box 84, Folder 837)
      - Portugal (Box 84, Folder 838)
      - United States (Box 84, Folder 839-840)
      - miscellaneous (Box 84, Folder 841-845)
      - miscellaneous (Box 85, Folder 846-847)
      - miscellaneous, research notes, memoranda (Box 85, Folder 848-853)
      - research notes, memoranda (Box 86, Folder 854-858)
    - International claims precedents - research notes (Box 87, Folder 859)
    - Foreign claims - research notes, bibliography (Box 87, Folder 860)
    - Requirement of Continuity of Nationality in Claims Presented by Heirs -research report (Box 87, Folder 861)
    - Summary of Claims By and Against the U.S. Settled Since 1906 - Vol. I (Box 87, Folder 862)
    - Summary of Claims By and Against the U.S. Settled Since 1906 - Vol. II (Box 87, Folder 863)
    - Inter Ocean Oil Company v. Great Britain, 1941-1949 (Box 87, Folder 864-865)
    - Sigg-Fehr Case (Swiss Government), -1939-1941 (Box 88, Folder 866-867)
    - Inter-American Commercial Arbitration Commission, 1934 (Box 88, Folder 868)
    - Creole Petroleum Corp. - Venezuela, 1945-1946 (Box 88, Folder 869)
    - Chester Concession negotiations, 1935 (Box 88, Folder 870-872)
    - Argentina - foreign loans, 1917 (Box 88, Folder 873)
    - U.S. as creditor and debtor - memoranda, pamphlets, 1925-1931 (Box 88, Folder 874)
    - China - foreign loans, 1918, 1926 (Box 88, Folder 875)
    - Columbia - foreign loans, 1933 (Box 89, Folder 876)
    - Bolivia - foreign loans, 1931 (Box 89, Folder 877)
    - Brazil - foreign loans, 1929 (Box 89, Folder 878)
    - Venezuela - foreign loans, 1930 (Box 89, Folder 879)
    - Great Britain - foreign loans, 1937 (Box 89, Folder 879)
    - Permanent Court of Arbitration - awards, 1902-1914 (Box 89, Folder 880)
    - Permanent Court of International Justice
      - Austrian and Italian briefs on German-Austrian customs regime, 1931 (Box 89, Folder 881)
      - German and Czechoslovakian brief on German-Austrian customs regime, 1931 (Box 89, Folder 882)
      - French brief on German-Austrian customs regime, 1933-1934 (Box 89, Folder 883)
    - World Court, 1931 (Box 89, Folder 884)
    - Oil monopoly cases - Sweden, Persia, Uruguay, 1933-1934 (Box 89, Folder 885)
    - Peruvian-Ecuadoran Boundary Case - research notes (Box 89, Folder 886)
    - Peruvian-Ecuadoran boundary dispute background memorandum (Spanish text) (Box 90, Folder 887)
    - Peruvian boundary-dispute, 1937 (Box 90, Folder 888-889)
    - Rumania - land reform (Box 90, Folder 890)
    - Yugoslavia - land reform (Box 90, Folder 891)
    - "Restraints on Neutral Trade in Arms Imposed Since 1854" by P. Moorison (Box 90, Folder 892)
    - Study of British controls over neutral trade, 1914-1918 by L. W. Fowles, 1938 (Box 90, Folder 893)
    - Newspaper clippings re: economic warfare, 1930's-1940's (Box 90, Folder 894)
    - Tientsin British Committee of Information - memoranda, 1926-1929 (Box 90, Folder 895)
    - Alien property custodian, 1934 (Box 90, Folder 896)
    - Flick Case, 1947 (Box 90, Folder 897)
    - "Agreements Relating to the Obligations Resulting from the Treaty of Trianon, 1930" - memoranda (Box 90, Folder 898)
  - International law: conferences and miscellaneous research topics
    - League of Nations, First Codification Conference, Geneva, 1928 - communiques (Box 91, Folder 899)
    - League of Nations - Conference on the Codification of International Law
      - memoranda, minutes, 1930 (Box 91, Folder 900-903)
      - memoranda, minutes, 1930 (Box 92, Folder 904-909)
    - Conference of Teachers of International Law, 1931-1933 May (Box 93, Folder 910-913)
    - Union Panamericana - Perfeccionamiento y Coor-dinacion de los Instrumentos Interamericanos de Paz Tomo III, IV, V, 1940 (Box 93, Folder 914)
    - Committee of Experts on the Codification of International Law, 1937-1946 (Box 93, Folder 915-916)
    - American Society of International Law - annual meeting, 1937 (Box 94, Folder 917)
    - American Society of International Law, 1940-1945 (Box 94, Folder 918)
    - State Insolvency Investigation, 1930-1943 (Box 94, Folder 919-927)
    - Conference on Germany After the War - memoranda, 1944 (Box 95, Folder 928)
    - American Bar Association
      - Committee on International Legal Problems Raised by War Conditions, 1942-1944 (Box 95, Folder 929)
      - International and Comparative Law Section, 1941-1946 (Box 95, Folder 930)
      - Committee on Development of International Law Through Conferences, 1938-1946 (Box 95, Folder 931)
    - International Congress of Comparative Law, 1929-1931 November (Box 95, Folder 932-937)
    - International Congress of Comparative Law, 1931 December - 1932 December (Box 96, Folder 938-941)
    - International Congress of Comparative Law - Governmental Responsibility Reports, 1932 (Box 96, Folder 942-943)
    - International Congress of Comparative Law, 1933-1934 (Box 96, Folder 944)
    - International Academy of Comparative Law - Second International Congress, 1937 (Box 97, Folder 945)
    - International Congress of Comparative Law - Reports on Declaratory Judgments, 1932 (Box 97, Folder 946-948)